Vincent R. Taijeron

6/3 Shevchenko Ave Odessa, Ukraine 65058

Mobile: +38 067 371 4805

Email: vincent.taijeron@gmail.com

Web: www.taijeronv.info

## **RESUME SUMMARY**

I am a competent and reliable simulation specialist with 15+ years of experience training, educating, and operating in the military domain. I am eager to contribute my experience and skills to a group of professionals dedicated to developing teams and individuals to meet their full potential.

## **EXPERIENCE**

Monitoring Officer, Organization for Security and Cooperation in Europe/PAE Sep 2014 - Present

- Standardized team operations by applying military planning methods that improved the team's coordination and efficiency during operations.
- Planned and supervised the execution of four "2nd of May" patrols, ensuring the team's safety.
- Effectively managed a team of 21 individual personalities ensuring a peaceful work environment.
- Monitored over 400 kilometers of the Transnistrian border, providing the OSCE situational awareness regarding the security situation.

Curriculum Developer, Alion Science and Technology, Odessa, Ukraine Aug 2013 – Sept 2014

- Advised the Commandant Major General Gulayk on the best way to integrate our NATO program into the 2015 academic year curriculum.
- Designed and taught a program of instruction to 2nd, 3rd, and 4th-year cadets, furthering their understanding of NATO offensive and defensive operations.
- Improved the cadet's ability to make decisions and solve problems by implementing the "Follow Me" software into their program of instruction.
- Developed a block of instruction featuring NATO mechanized infantry and armor operations for 35 students attending the Captain's Advanced Course, giving them an in-depth understanding.

Embedded Police Mentor, DynCorp International, Khowst Province, Afghanistan Jun 2011 – Aug 2013

- Mentored a special unit of 10 Afghan patrolmen tasked with augmenting coalition forces and securing FOB Salerno.
- Developed and taught a one-week induction program to my ten-man police unit, improving their ability to operate with their US Army partners.
- Assisted 33 patrolmen in planning independent night patrols.
- Participated in over 75 mounted and dismounted combat patrols with the US Army while advising the Afghan police.

West Point Simulation Center Manager, West Point, West Point, NY Aug 2004-Jun 2011

- Integrated Virtual Battlespace 2 into cadet basic training, providing over 1000 cadets an opportunity to practice squad fire and movement techniques before going to the field.
- Implemented the VBS into the Summer Leadership Seminar, providing future cadets an opportunity to experience simulations training at the academy.
- Taught thousands of cadets to use VBS in support of the military science curriculum, cadet basic training, and other special events.
- Enhanced the Military Science 3 and 4 programs by integrating the "Follow Me" program, which was used to practice making tactical decisions.
- Incorporated the Follow Me simulation into three military science courses, one college major (Defense Strategic Studies) and two leadership courses for the Department of Behavioral Science and Leadership.

## **KEY SKILLS**

Content Development Virtual Battle Space
Gaming Microsoft Office
Simulations Writing

## **EDUCATION**

Guam Community College, Technical Electronics, 1981 Central Texas College, General Studies, 1989